<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Versatile Spirit</title>
    <subtitle>Ran Wei&#39;s Blog</subtitle>
    <description>Welcome to my website! 
</description>
    <link>http://wendyran.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://wendyran.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 16:51:19 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 16:51:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Blog History and Why I Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I started my first personal blog using &lt;a href=&quot;http://spaces.live.com&quot;&gt;MSN Space&lt;/a&gt; (or Windows Live Spaces, shut down in 2011) starting summer 2006. It was after I graduated from my &lt;a href=&quot;http://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E5%8D%8E%E4%B8%AD%E5%B8%88%E8%8C%83%E5%A4%A7%E5%AD%A6%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E9%99%84%E5%B1%9E%E4%B8%AD%E5%AD%A6&quot;&gt;high school&lt;/a&gt; and before I went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zhejiang_University&quot;&gt;Zhejiang University&lt;/a&gt; for my undergraduate study. The MSN Space is where I kept a record of my thoughts after the stressful high school and before I entered my colorful college life. Since then, like many others, I’ve written in several different blogs: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ycool.com&quot;&gt;ycool&lt;/a&gt;(previously ‘yculblog’; Chinese name: 歪酷), &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.sina.com&quot;&gt;sina blog&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://hi.baidu.com&quot;&gt;baidu space&lt;/a&gt; (closed on May 7th, 2015) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;wordpress&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my graduate school at the Ohio State University where I’m pursuing my Ph.D. in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stat.osu.edu&quot;&gt;Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, I continued my enthusiasm for blogging. I have been updating my offline blog all the time but it was only until recently that I really had a chance to start building my own blog website, with the help from &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a natural urge to record the ever past moments and the exciting thoughts that ever hit me. Time passes so fast yet there were so many things you wanted to carve into something that would never vanish. This is the general reason of me blogging. While humans’ thoughts can be so subtle that typing speed could hardly catch up with the flow, I still would like to try my best. Or else most things would just pass by without a clue of ever being existed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;English is not my native language. Even though I started learning it at an early age and have lived in the U.S. for almost 5 years, I still want to keep improving my English skills. Writing blogs, on the other hand, would definitely help a lot, not to mention how it would contribute to my Ph.D. dissertation writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have mentioned, statistics is my major. So you are going to see lots of posts about data science and statistics in this blog. I enjoy taking photographs as well so this is another category you are going to see in this website.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://wendyran.github.io/jekyll/update/2015/05/26/why-i-blog-and-my-blog-history.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://wendyran.github.io/jekyll/update/2015/05/26/why-i-blog-and-my-blog-history.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
